You know, 2 years ago, I was I was one
of six um independent journalists who
were invited to have lunch with the
Russian ambassador to the United States.
And
we we went to the to the residence. It
was this big, formal deal. So, it was
the ambassador, the deputy ambassador,
and like three of his staff members, and
six of us journalists. And he had read
um articles that all of us had written.
He actually quoted them, which really
struck me.
And the reason for the lunch was
for the most part, he wanted our ideas
on how the US and Russia could cooperate
in a time of war.
And I gave my standard thing,
counterterrorism, counterproliferation,
counternarcotics.
Um
but
the thing that made him angriest
was
how the State Department pushes LGBTQ
on countries where it is culturally
unacceptable.
And he said, "You know, we don't even
mind being adversaries on some of these
issues. Our interests are different
sometimes from American interests." He
said, "You're right, we can cooperate on
counterterrorism. We can cooperate on on
counterproliferation. That's a great
idea, no problem. But don't force us to
accept trans people in our government.
Don't force us to to accept LGBTQ people
in positions of authority in the
Orthodox Church. We will not do it. You
don't respect our culture." And he said,
"That's a bigger problem than not
respecting our policies."
>> Why do they do it? Cuz like I I like
living in a country where people are are
are free to be themselves and do what
they want to do. That's a beautiful part
of America.
>> Agreed, 100%.
>> It's different when you're pushing like
I would in in fairness to like my gay
friends, like this is not This is
pushing like some sort of
business-commissioned ideology on places
to make them probably pay more attention
to it in a negative light than they
would have in the first place if you
didn't do it.
>> Exactly. Exactly.
>> So, why do they do it?
>> People Some of the people who might be
impacted by like eight eight thousand
dollars to promote DEI among LGBTQ
groups in Cyprus.
Well,
everybody in Cyprus is Greek Orthodox,
right? The Orthodox Church of Cyprus.
There is no such thing as LGBTQ
in a in a culture like that. It's a
conservative culture. It's offensive. I
I recognize that it's only eight
thousand dollars. And I'm glad that
[laughter] we that we have it here. I'm
glad. I welcome it. I celebrate it.
Truly.
But we we shouldn't be imposing our own
values, our own cultural values on
countries that don't want it.
>> Yeah.
I don't I it just
it seems so especially when you look at
like I was saying the amounts. It's not
doing anything. So when you look at like
the the devil's advocate to like USAID,
and we can talk about this cuz I think
you'll probably have a lot of thoughts
here, is that
it has to do with this idea of soft
power.
>> Mhm.
>> And
we already mentioned the extreme example
of like pushing drugs in other countries
earlier, but where there are countries
like I don't know, China, Russia, Iran,
who are running around and maybe
building roads in places to curry favor.
>> Oh, I'm so glad you brought that up.
>> Or give debt you know, basically create
debts and say don't worry about it, but
now we get to do this with you. I
understand why the United States would
want to have things like that.
I just don't want to see it have stupid
[__] like this, and I don't want to see
it not have oversight.
>> See, I get that.
>> And then that leads to the question of
why is it that the Chinese are building
ports and roads and hospitals and
airports all over the world and we're
doing that?
>> Right.
>> What do we have to show for that? We
have nothing. Nothing. It's like
democracy in Afghanistan. This has long
been a big deal for me. Why in blazes
did we force Afghanistan into a
Western-style democracy when in the
three thousand years of of country's
history, they never had a Western-style
democracy. They had this system called
the Loya Jirga, which worked.
>> What was the Loya Jirga?
>> It's a consultative council of tribal
chieftains.
And so, if you and I are in a dispute, I
I say that my land ends here, and you
say no, it ends here, and we have a
conflict with one another, we go to the
Loya Jirga. And they we each give our
side, and they settle the dispute. Or
um I want to be the village, you know,
tax collector, let's say. We go to the
Loya Jirga, I make my pitch, the other
guy makes his pitch, the Loya Jirga
votes, uh they choose, you know, this
guy.
>> Oligarchs instead of kings.
>> Yeah. All right. Right.
So, we said, "No, no, we we recognize
you guys have been doing that for
thousands of years, but we don't like
that. Instead, we're going to have uh
an election,
and we got this guy, Hamid Karzai,
and his brother's got a nice restaurant
in Baltimore. You can You can have lunch
at his Afghan restaurant in Baltimore.
It's very popular.
>> And so, that's real?
>> Uh-huh.
>> Really did?
>> In Baltimore?
>> Yeah.
>> There's like six good blocks in
Baltimore.
>> I know, that's about it. [laughter] And
And they still call it Greektown.
>> Yeah.
>> [snorts]
>> And uh
And they're like, "Well, we don't uh we
don't want that kind of system." And we
said, "Yeah, we're we're not asking you.
We're telling you." But then,
you know, we're not pushing democracy on
Saudi Arabia,
or on Kuwait, or Bahrain, or or even
Egypt, which actually had a democracy
for a minute. But when the wrong guy got
elected, then
we said, "Now, al-Qaeda would be okay,
just about now."
>> [laughter]
>> Why? Why did we choose Saudi Arabia? I
think it's more self-explanatory. Yeah.
But like, Egypt, why do we decide that's
okay there, but not in Afghanistan?
>> Because the Egyptian populace
um has an intense dislike of Israel,
which is in opposition to our foreign
policy.
And there are so many poor people. We're
afraid of a broad uprising there.
>> Mhm. They'll throw us out. You know,
it's it's going to be chaos.
>> What's different about Afghanistan
though? Cuz there's a lot of poor people
there as well. Was it the geography more
than anything they thought they could
get away with it?
>> In part it's geography and in part it's
population. There aren't that many
people in Afghanistan and we thought we
can we can push these people around and
we can supply them with whatever they
need. We have bases in Uzbekistan,
Tajikistan. We had the drone base in in
Pakistan that nobody knew about until
until a really smart thinking reporter
filed a Freedom of Information Act
request for all drone fuel deliveries in
Pakistan.
And they're like, "Oh, sure. Here you
go. All the drone
>> got fired for that.
>> [laughter]
>> It's like, "What's the harm in asking
where all the fuel is coming from? Or
where where the fuel is going?" It's
going right here to this base. Oh, wait
a minute. That's a secret base. Oh,
sorry.
>> Oh, man.
>> Yeah.
But we just pushed them around and it
didn't work. I I say often too that
that the Taliban did not descend from
the moon, right? And just They didn't
softly land in Afghanistan and take
over. These are the the husbands, the
fathers, the brothers of Afghan women.
They're they're Afghan families. This is
who they chose to be led by.
They had 20 years of American
leadership. They didn't like it.
And so they chose the Taliban.
>> Well, we didn't leave. That's the other
problem. We put in figureheads. We tried
to push, as you just laid out
beautifully, democracy on a on a country
where that wasn't necessarily what they
wanted or what their history wanted. And
then we also got, oh I don't know,
tangled up in a [__] war in Iraq. So
we pulled resources
and there was all kinds of [__] that
that went on that led to that steep
decline and it's not even like the whole
population supports the Taliban, but the
Taliban was able to say, "Hey, we're not
as bad as this." And enough people were
like, "All right, [__] it."
>> Yep. That's exactly right. You know,
there was another thing too. I remember
being there in like 2007
maybe. 2007
and we had come up with this just
terrible idea
to combat corruption, right?
Corruption's endemic. It's just a part
of the culture.
So, we decided that
the police chief
in each
province
would have to come from another
province.
>> Mhm.
>> Right? So, the police chief in a Pashtun
area was a Hazara, for example. And the
police chief in a Baloch area was from,
you know,
the the border with Tajikistan.
And they said, "Well, that way, you
know, there's no connection between the
police chief and the populace. They
don't have anything in common, so it's
going to make bribery go away, and it's
going to make everybody honest." No.
They just started killing all the police
chiefs.
>> Mhm.
>> They're like, "I'm not going to I
Where's this guy from? He's got Asian
eyes. He's not a Pashtun."
>> Right.
>> they put a bullet in his head.
It's like, that's a That was a dumb
idea. Who's Who thought of that?
>> There's a lot of people who play fantasy
football with governments sitting in
offices in DC and maybe even Langley and
[clears throat] stuff, and doesn't mean
they're dumb, it means that they're not
thinking.
>> No.
And they just have no cultural
understanding and no understanding of
history. I will say
that for the most part
the working level
foreign service officers at the State
Department do have that understanding of
history. And they tend to focus on
specific geographic areas. So, if you're
an Arabist, you speak Arabic,
you're going to spend probably the
entirety of your career in the Middle
East until you become an ambassador.
And then you'll probably spend most of
it in the Middle East even after you've
become an ambassador.
And, you know, elsewhere in government,
USAID, CIA,
Pentagon, forget it. I never met anybody
at the Pentagon who spoke Arabic.
>> They live in their own worlds.
What is it What Where Where is the State
Department in all this? That's actually
good you bring that up. Because there
the State Department, and you've done a
great job explaining this in the past. I
know Bustamante's talked about this in
the past and Jim Waller and those guys
like they will house a lot of people who
maybe work for the agency or even
sometimes the Pentagon like undercover.
And then they're also there to be the
diplomats and have the embassy and you
know, shake hands and kiss babies.
But for things like USAID
to happen, you have the intelligence
agencies potentially using it as like a
money laundering operation to get stuff
done.
>> the dangerous part.
>> But does the State Department know
that's happening or can they just not do
anything about it?
>> Yes and yes.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. There there's a formal written
agreement between the CIA and the State
Department um on that addresses cover
issues.
You know, sometimes
for for for most of my career,
actually for the entirety of my career,
now that I'm thinking about it, um
I was under what was called nominal
cover. Like, "Oh, where do you work?"
"Ah, State Department."
>> Right.
>> But there was a cover that could back
that up. You couldn't call the State
Department and say, "Can I speak to
John?" and then, you know, they route
the call to me. That just didn't exist.
>> Oh, you didn't even have a cover back
up?
>> No, no, no, no.
>> Oh.
>> No. No. I was declared to so many
intelligence services it wouldn't have
made it a difference anyway. So, um
So, there's this formal agreement
between the State Department and the CIA
like there is between the the CIA and
other governmental bodies.
USAID is an unusual situation though.
I never ever encountered a CIA officer
who was embedded in USAID. I don't think
that that happens.
Um it it wouldn't make sense anyway
because yeah, because when you're when
you're embedded,
you have to do that cover job for 8
hours
and then you go out and do your CIA job
for 8 hours. That's right. So,
if if you're going to be given some kind
of official cover, you don't want it to
be USAID where you actually have to do
the work,
you know? You want to be
I I got to be very careful here. Um, but
you want to be in a position where you
can sort of blend the two.
>> Hm.
>> Yeah. [clears throat]
>> Why do you have to be careful here?
>> Because um
the details are classified.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, let's not have another trial.
>> No, no no more trials for me, thank you.
>> So you got to blend the two. We'll leave
it at that.
>> the reason I said that this is a a
problem
is that to use to use a phrase that I
heard this week on the news um USAID was
was a beachhead for the CIA in the State
Department. That's not what USAID is
supposed to do. USAID is supposed to be,
you know, digging water wells and
training doctors and, you know, building
sewage treatment plants and electrical
grids and helping people develop. It's
the Agency for International
Development.
>> Which was like John F. Kennedy's
>> That was the plan. Yeah. USAID, the
Peace Corps, and VISTA were all created
at the same time
>> by John Kennedy.
>> You know, that it was a great idea.
>> Yeah.
>> But the CIA
the CIA moved right in as soon as
Kennedy was killed. By 1964, the CIA was
running covert operations out of USAID.
This has all been declassified. It's all
>> Okay, this is declassified.
>> declassified. You It's available at the
um
at the National Security Archives at
George Washington University.
>> Okay, so for this example, since it's
declassified, can you explain what that
one looked like?
>> Yeah.
>> Cuz now I'm a bit confused cuz you're
saying you wouldn't go undercover there,
but is it blend of the two?
>> They did not have They did not have
people undercover
uh at USAID. What they did is they ran
covert operations through USAID.
>> English.
>> Uh okay.
In 1972,
Ted Kennedy wrote a letter to the CIA
and he said this is also available
declassified online. So he said, "I
heard that the CIA was paying Laotian
mercenaries
through USAID.
>> Just cutting
>> Okay.
>> payroll checks.
>> Yeah.
>> Um is that true?
And so he got a letter back from from
Henry Kissinger who was the Secretary of
State at the time.
>> Real straight shooter, too.
>> Oh yeah, yeah. He's never going to
obfuscate.
>> Phenomenal guy.
>> He got an identical letter from the CIA,
like identical to the word.
Um saying yeah.
We're using USAID essentially to launder
money and pay these Laotian mercenaries
to fight communists.
And
Kennedy's letter said, "Did you pay
these people in 1969?" And he said,
"Yeah, we paid them in '69 and '70 and
'71 and '72. Like what are you going to
do about it, Kennedy?"
Well, that was just one of many many
operations that that was paid for
through USAID. Here's another thing. And
and this might be a better explanation.
They're
>> I I love when John starts cooking.
>> Really good. Chef Curry with the shot.
Keep going.
>> There used to be a a senator, Democratic
senator from Wisconsin by the name of
William Proxmire.
Proxmire was famous for a couple of
reasons. First, he won the seat that uh
Joseph McCarthy vacated when he drank
himself to death.
>> Okay.
>> Right?
>> Yeah.
>> So he was a liberal Democrat. There he
is, Bill Proxmire. And he was famous
also for never spending a single dollar
to get reelected. He said "The people of
Wisconsin know my voting record. They
either like it or they don't like it."
>> And he got elected?
>> Time after time after time. Yeah. He
finally retired like in the '70s, like
'76 or '78, something like that.
>> I've never heard of that before at any
point. When did he retire? He It looks
like 1989.
>> '89. Okay, so he was around for a long
time. From '57 to '89. So he hated
government waste more than anything in
the world. And he decided to bestow an
award, kind of a gag award, called the
Golden Fleece Award for the fleecing of
the American taxpayer. And he would do
it every month. Every month he would
call
>> I like that so much.
>> the Golden Fleece Award. The problem was
a lot of what he identified as
government waste was actually secret CIA
programming.
>> So he couldn't say it.
>> No, he said it anyway.
>> Oh, he did? And he didn't get arrested?
>> The CIA was apoplectic.
>> I'll bet.
>> Because he would say, you know, $5
million
dollars to study, you know, gay monkeys
in Gabon. [laughter]
And he's like, what the [__] IS THIS?
THIS IS a waste of the taxpayer's money.
Well, of course there was no $5 million
dollars to study gay monkeys in Gabon.
That's just what they called it. Yeah.
>> So that the CIA cuz you can't like go on
to Google and look for the CIA budget.
It's not
>> You can't, but do they have to create
like a shell company on the other side?
Meaning like a company called like
research for gay monkey studies.
>> There are probably really mercenaries
behind it who are like thank you for the
money.
>> There are at least hundreds of those.
>> Right. Okay.
>> Maybe thousands.
>> got to try.
>> They got to try.
>> Got it.
>> Yes. Yeah, but the thing is
the the CIA's budget is hidden all
around the rest of the federal budget.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay, it's not just in the State
Department, not just in the Defense
Department or the Commerce Department,
it's everywhere. And so they'll say $5
million dollars for gay monkeys in Gabon
and they'll put that at USAID. Or
they'll put it in, you know, the
whatever, some fund for the National
Geographic Society or whatever. They're
not really going to spend that money on
that. They're going to spend it to, you
know, buy weapons for lotion mercenaries
or, you know, bring drugs to Los Angeles
or whatever.
>> Okay. So let me ask a direct question
then on this that you may not know the
answer to, but in theory you could. Did
we really spend $50 million dollars on
condoms in Mozambique or did that fund
some sort of like rebel army there?
>> You know, if that were $50,000, I'd say
yeah, we we did that. If it's $50
dollars, I'd say that's nuts and it's
probably something else.
>> Okay, that's making sense now. So, this
is a tale as old as time and they as you
said there's declassified things
involving like Henry Kissinger where
they admit
>> Oh, yeah.
>> this.
>> And they went beyond that. I mean, let's
go into the into the early 2000s.
>> Please.
>> Uh in 2003,
>> We didn't do anything wrong in 2003.
Stop. Stop right there. I don't know
where people found the time to get all
these things done.
>> a great year.
>> Oof. There everything was right.
>> Slam dunk.
>> Slam dunk. It was a slam dunk, wasn't
it?
>> [laughter]
>> In 2003, we created
a Facebook alternative called ZunZuneo.
And it just appeared in Cuba. Like, oh,
look, this this
this
this Facebook copy and it just appeared
>> Cuba libre.
>> the Cuban
internet one [snorts] day.
>> Yeah.
>> And uh
>> I didn't know they had that.
>> Yeah, ZunZuneo. And so, it was supposed
to um encourage Cubans to initiate uh
the equivalent of the Arab Spring and
overthrow the Castros.
And nobody signed up for ZunZuneo.
Nobody.
>> They couldn't get anyone to sign up?
>> No, people are like, "Nah, we're not
interested."
>> They didn't like drop some flyers with
like prizes? No?
>> Nah.
>> Low effort.
>> Yeah.
>> They weren't interested.
>> That's how I like my overthrows though,
[laughter] John.
>> Softly.
>> You do it online, you piss them off,
everyone gets their tiki torches, they
have a nice little meeting, and then
poof, new leader.
>> Yep.
>> Nothing wrong with that.
>> That's exactly right. Uh in in 2013,
they um
they infiltrated the Bolivian uh media
to try to overthrow Evo Morales.
>> How they do this?
>> Uh they just started buying uh
journalists.
Just say, "Hey, how much do you make?
$500 a month? Okay, here's $5,000. Write
this article saying that Evo Morales was
caught with a 6-year-old girl."
>> Yeah.
>> They're like, "Okay,
I can do that."
>> How often does stuff like that still
happen?
>> Oh, every single day.
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
>> All over the world.
>> Meaning it's not just concentrated in
one, two places of interest. This stuff
is happening all the time.
>> All over the world. And you know, with
the with the advance of technology, too,
it just makes it easier and easier.
Although it diffuses it because, you
know, it's not just ABC, CBS, NBC, The
New York Times, The Washington Post, The
Wall Street Journal, The LA Times. Now,
there are millions. I mean,
we're all journalists. Any any blogger
Anybody any slob who rolls out of bed in
the morning and makes a YouTube video
can be a
>> I feel attacked.
>> a journalist.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to
>> It's okay. You saw my bed before
[laughter] we got started.
>> No, that's okay. You're wearing a
pirate's hat and that's that's all that
matters to me.
>> John, but Keep falling [laughter] in
But yes, as you were saying
>> It happens every day.
>> Yeah.
So,
if we had to steel man something like
that, would you say that doing cuz that
doesn't sit right with me that you're
you are infecting what's supposed to be
sources of news that's supposed to in
theory be unbiased? So, it just feels
dirty in every way. I know it happens to
us. It's the same argument as earlier. I
know it happens to us all the time.
Do you think if you had to choose poison
pill, it's better to do that than it is
to actually hire rebels to go in and
kill the people in charge that we don't
like?
>> Yes.
>> Now, it gets hard cuz it's like, well,
what do we do and what do we not do?
>> And and your chances of success are low.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, look at look at what the
Russians were accused of doing in 2016
and what they actually did in 2016. The
Democratic narrative is that the
Russians essentially
bought the 2016 election for Donald
Trump, right? That's all been all been
proven false.
>> Yep. Yep. So, what did the Russians
actually do?
They spent $50,000
on YouTube ads.
Okay? None of the YouTube ads were
political.
25,000
half of it was spent after the election
was over.
So, you have $25,000 left and they're
all like memes of kittens and puppies
and flowers.
Almost all of that money was spent in
states that were already solidly red or
solidly blue.
>> Mhm.
>> That's not stealing the election. That's
somebody some idiot wasted $50,000.
>> Like we were looking at up here.
>> Mhm.
Yeah. So, we do what the Russians do,
what the Chinese do, what the Cubans,
the Iranians, the Israelis, the French,
the British, everybody does it.
>> So, why did they cuz we can look at that
now because so much of this has been
disproven. You know, it was always crazy
to me. There were so many things like
just in general that if you wanted to
attack Trump on, you could attack him,
but they had to come up with stuff.
>> Yeah. Why attack him on the fake stuff?
>> That's what I'm saying. Like stuff and
and they made it sound very bad, I'll
say that. So, I see why it could make a
story. But they attacked him on things
that now hindsight being 20/20, it's
like it was always going to come out
that this isn't real. The evidence is
all there.
>> You know, when you assemble this
blue-ribbon panel of the the greatest
minds in government to look at the
evidence,
they're going to find the truth.
>> Unless they're the Warren Commission.
>> Unless they're the Warren Commission or
maybe the 9/11 Commission.
Well, I don't I don't want to talk about
that.
>> Okay.
>> And uh no, I'm just kidding.
>> Pin put in that.
>> [laughter]
>> We're coming back.
>> And um
yeah.
I mean, if they're if they're
legitimately doing their job, they're
going to find Look, we we have no
evidence. The Russians didn't steal the
election for Donald Trump.
That's just the way it is.
>> There was so much There were so many
people though cuz you're making me think
with the media thing. There were so many
people in the media who were Now we can
say it
creating evidence.
>> Oh my god, Rachel Maddow as an example.
>> I On my show one day
we played a clip of Rachel Maddow saying
Russia, Moscow, or Putin
90 times in the first [clears throat]
hour of her show the night before.
It was ridiculous.
>> And she was ripping Mitt Romney for
saying it 4 years before that. Remember
that? He got like laughed off the stage.
Obama was like, "Cold war called once
their policy back."
And everyone's like, "Ha, he said
Russia." And then it was like the main
keyword.
>> Yeah. It sure was.
Do you Do you think that
Well, let's get to the bigger question
here.
Do you think that like
>> powers that be in the bureaucracy and I
mean this is what the internet says, but
do you think there is any legitimacy to
people in the bureaucracy
besides like those two idiots at the FBI
who really were actually working to
attribute things to other places when in
fact it was quite literally them doing
it to stop Donald Trump from getting
into power?
>> [sighs]
>> Boy, that's a good question.
>> Yeah. You know how it looks.
>> Yeah.
>> Regardless of politics, you know how it
looks. Yeah.
>> You know, honestly, I have to say
probably yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, probably.
And and that's a surprise to me because
when I when I worked at the CIA
we generally had no idea what our
colleagues politics were. Genuinely. I
sat next to this one guy for 6 years. I
didn't have the foggiest idea if he was
a Democrat, a Republican, or an
independent. No idea. There was a woman
I worked with, this is in like '96,
and she got in trouble
like written up because she put a Bob
Dole for President bumper sticker in her
cubicle.
>> Oh, wow.
>> "That has to come down and you're
getting written up and you have to go to
HR and you know, we work for the for the
country. We don't choose sides."
That's how it used to be at the FBI as
well.
And that really seemed to change
dramatically around 2016.
>> What do you think it was? Do Well, let
me even ask a hypothetical in there.
Cuz I always wonder this. I'm like,
obviously I know Trump says a lot of
[__] and like, you know, he's an
outsider and all this.
But like
do you think that there's some sort of
intelligence? I don't know what it would
be.
That they know about him.
That they think it's just so dangerous.
That they're willing to completely lift
the veil on their
not caring about these elections and
>> No.
>> and saying like [__] it get him out of
there.
>> Somebody would have leaked it. You know,
going back to um
to the um
Christopher Steele report. You know, I
worked with Chris Steele.
>> Wait, this is the guy that had the piss
memo, right?
>> Right. Yeah. He he was an MI6
officer.
>> You worked with?
>> Yeah, we did an operation together. In
in London in the '90s.
And the funny thing about it is he was
like the guy at MI6 that all the other
MI6 guys wanted to be like. That's how
highly respected he was.
I I enjoy
>> Christopher Steele.
>> Mhm.
>> Golden showers.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay, please continue.
>> So
I have I have a theory.
He went from
the James Bond
kind of officer that
that every MI6 guy wanted to be
to this caricature because
when you're collecting intelligence
when you're an operations officer
collecting intelligence
no matter how outrageous the
intelligence might be you send it back
to your headquarters and the analysts go
over it. And the analysts say this is
[__] this is great, this is
a possibility, this is a probability.
You just turn it over the analysts.
So if he had been in MI6 and a source
told him
that Donald Trump paid Russian
prostitutes to pee on Barack Obama's
hotel bed.
Um the analysts would say this is stupid
and it wouldn't get published. Cuz
there's no other information to
corroborate this.
>> Mhm.
>> But in private practice there is no team
of analysts to go over the the
intelligence.
>> Cuz he was out by then.
>> He was out by then. And he was paid
by the Clinton campaign. Although there
were reports that he was initially hired
by the Ted Cruz campaign and then
[laughter] Cruz walked away from it.
>> I intend.
>> Uh-huh. And then Hillary said, "We'll
take it."
So, there was no team of analysts to vet
the information and to tell the Clinton
campaign, "This is nonsense. This is
true. This is maybe. This is I don't
know. We have to ask other questions,
find other sources." There was nobody to
do that. And so,
he did what he always did in MI6. He
just write it up and send it in.
And then let the next group figure out
if it's true or not.
>> think it's just literally because he may
not have endorsed it. He just had what
he found and he didn't have government
analysts on the other side. So, he said
they'll take care of that.
>> Yeah.
I think that's exactly what happened.
>> Now, how All right, back up a sec. How
were you working with this guy?
Was this Was this the Greek stuff?
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, [__] Okay.
Can you talk about this at all?
>> In generalities.
>> That's good enough.
>> I became the master of the old files
on Greek terrorism.
I I took this issue so seriously. It
actually cost me my first marriage.
I was obsessed with Greek terrorism.
>> Yep.
>> And then they tried to kill me
in Athens.
>> You told that story.
>> So,
I would go through these files. These
files some of them were 25 years old
just looking for a lead. A lead that
maybe had been overlooked 10, 20, 25
years ago.
And I found a lead. It was a connection
between the Greeks and Carlos the
Jackal.
And nobody had ever talked to this guy.
So, I'm like, "Where is this guy? Would
anyone have any idea where this guy is?"
So, which guy?
Oh, but
>> The The connection.
>> Yeah.
>> So,
I wrote a cable to headquarters and I
said,
"I've identified this guy that I think
is the middleman between the Greeks and
Carlos the Jackal.
Um do we have any idea where he is?
I think he's probably in Lebanon." I
said.
I get a cable back and they said, no,
he's
he's living in London.
I said, how in the heck is he living in
London?
They said he converted to Christianity,
married some English woman, and he's
living in London.
I said, I got I got to see him.